Register of the Lester Armour papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Lester Armour papers
1941-1953
71065
Hoover Institution Archives
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Class notes and correspondence relating to the Naval Air Combat Intelligence Officers School, Quonset Point, Rhode Island, and the Aviation Intelligence Center, Pacific Ocean Areas; and official orders, reports, correspondence, photographs, and other materials related to the U.S. Navy and the Office of Strategic Services during World War II. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Armour, Lester, 1895-1971
Access
Collection is open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1971.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1895 March 21 Born, Chicago, Illinois
1918 B. A., Yale
1918-1919 Ensign, U.S. Naval Aviation
1941-1945 Captain, U.S. Naval Reserves Chairman of Board, Chief Executive Officer, Chicago National Bank.
1970 December 26 Died, Lake Forest, Illinois
Scope and Content of Collection
Class notes and correspondence relating to the Naval Air Combat Intelligence Officers School, Quonset Point, Rhode Island, and the Aviation Intelligence Center, Pacific Ocean Areas; and official orders, reports, correspondence, photographs, and other materials related to the U.S. Navy and the Office of Strategic Services during World War II.
United States. Naval Air Station (Quonset Point, R.I.); United States. Navy.; Military intelligence.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.
- Correspondence, 1942-1943 (Box 1)
  - Austin, J. S. (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - Barnes, J. H. (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - Batcheller, Adams (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - Bolling, R. H. (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Bray, J. G. (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - Caulkins, Daniel (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - Cheney, Ward (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - Clark, Edward H. (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - Coleman, John B. (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Colt, C. C. (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Davison, H. P. (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Emory, R. W. (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - Field, Joanne (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - Fuller, Frank (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Gates, Thomas (Box-folder 1: 15)
  - Grant, Clinton (Box-folder 1: 16)
  - Grosscup, P. B. (Box-folder 1: 17)
  - Hindley, C. R. (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Hines, R. J. (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Huggins, Frank B. (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Ingersoll, R. E. (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Jacobs, Randall (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Johnson, James P. (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Kent, R. (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - King, J. P. (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Lawrence, Blake (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - McNeely, Donald (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Mendell, C. W. (Box-folder 1: 28)
  - Minney, Martin (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Mitchell, John (Box-folder 1: 30)
  - Payne, H. G. (Box-folder 1: 31)
  - Van Peursem, R. (Box-folder 1: 32)
  - Saltzman, E. H. (Box-folder 1: 33)
  - Silzer, P. W. (Box-folder 1: 34)
  - Stark, Harold (Box-folder 1: 35)
  - Stone, E. F. (Box-folder 1: 36)
  - Teller, Steadman (Box-folder 1: 37)
  - Wead, F. W. (Box-folder 1: 38)
  - Wells, Charles (Box-folder 1: 39)
  - West, Paul (Box-folder 1: 40)
  - Wolfe, Albert B. (Box-folder 1: 41)
  - General memoranda (Box-folder 1: 42)
  - Unidentified correspondence (Box-folder 1: 43)
- Subject File (Box 1)
  - Naval Air Combat Intelligence Officers School (Box-folder 1: 44)
  - Naval Air Combat Intelligence Office, South Pacific/South West Pacific Area (Box-folder 1: 45)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1942-1943 (Reading room workstation)
  Scope and Contents note
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Available as PDF files. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder by date of creation.
  - 2010 release of records, 1942-1943
    - Diary of activities, circa 1942-1943
    - G. Edward Buxton memo to Lester Armour regarding orders, 1943 September 11
- Career File, 1941-1950 (Box 2)
  - Orders
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2: 1-2)
    - 1942-1945 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - Inactive duty papers, 1945 June-August (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - Navy miscellany
    - 1941-1943 (Box-folder 2: 5)
      Includes correspondence, passport materials with photo negative, promotion papers, and questionnaires.
    - 1944-1950 (Box-folder 2: 6)
      Includes medical examination forms, correspondence, applications for veterans compensation, and Navy questionnaires.
  - U.S. Navy Officer Service Record, 1942-1953 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - Office of Strategic Services, farewell gathering, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Awards, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    Includes The Order of the Dannebrog and the 10th Liberty Medal, awarded by the King of Denmark; the Bronze Star Medal and Battle Participation Award, awarded by the United States; the Croix de Guerre, awarded by France; and a signed dollar bill.
  - Legion of Merit, 1945 (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Report of the Advisory Committee of the Bureau of Naval Personnel, 1946 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Illinois State Bonus file, 1950 (Box-folder 2: 12)
- Photographs, 1942, undated (Box 2)
  - 1942 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Portraits, undated (Box-folder 2: 14)
- Correspondence II, 1942-1953 (Box 2)
  - General, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Navy, 1942-1953 (Box-folder 2: 16)
    Also contains Navy and U.S. Naval Reserve identity cards, as well as British alien identity registration.
  - Enclosures to "Personal Observation of Aviation Operational Intelligence in Great Britain,", 1942 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    A continuation of "Enclosure (A)" found in Folder 16, "Navy Correspondence, 1942-1953."